“创始吸血鬼”前情提要
ELlJAH: Previously on The Originals...
这座城市曾经是我的家
我要夺回来
This town was my home once.
I want it back.
你自由了
走得远远的，永远不要回来
You are free.
Go far away and never come back.
每个狼人在今晚都会
变成长毛利齿的野兽
Every werewolf will be a bundle
of fur and sharp teeth tonight
而你们被诅咒的新月狼族会变成…
whilst your cursed clan will be--
人类，但只能维持几小时
Human, but only for a few hours,
再变身只能等下个满月了
and won't be again
until the next full moon.
- 我叫杰克森
- 你就是那头一直看着我的狼
-I'm Jackson.
-You're the wolf who's been watching me.
你应该是我的妻子
You were supposed to be my wife.
这是研磨成糊状的草药
SABlNE:
It's herbs ground into paste.
下一次月圆，你的族人变成人类时
On the next full moon,
when your people become human,
给他们吃下，诅咒便会解除
feed it to them,
the curse will be broken.
我被下咒了
我不知道我还剩多长时间
I've been hexed,
and I don't know how long I have.
祖先们说如果我再滥用我的魔法
The ancestors said
they'd do horrible things to me
他们会严厉地惩罚我
if I misused my magic again.
马赛勒斯，你被驱逐了
Marcellus, you are hereby exiled.
如果我发现你的踪迹
你不会有好下场的
If I so much as find a trace of you,
it will not end well for you.
干得好，哥哥
你说话的语气开始像我了
Nicely done, brother.
You're beginning to sound like me.
人们说时间能治愈所有伤口
KLAUS: They say the passage of time
will heal all wounds.
但失去的越多
伤口就越深
But the greater the loss,
the deeper the cut.
你也越难走出其中，彻底痊愈
And the more difficult the process
to become whole again.
痛苦或许会消退
The pain may fade,
但伤疤会提醒我们曾经的痛苦
but scars serve as a reminder
of our suffering...
让我们越加下定决心
...and make the bearer
all the more resolved,
绝不让自己再受到伤害
never to be wounded again.
随着时间过去
So, as time moves along...
我们在诱惑中迷失
...we get lost in distractions.
在挫败中发泄
Act out in frustration.
用暴力来反抗
React with aggression.
屈服于愤怒
Give in to anger.
一直以来
And all the while...
我们密谋计划，等待着自己强大的一天
...we plot and plan
as we wait to grow stronger.
不知不觉中，时光流逝
And before we know it,
the time passes.
我们的伤口被治愈
We are healed.
准备好重新开始
Ready to begin anew.
听起来你已经战胜了自己内心的恶魔
Spoken like a man
who's made peace with his demons.
我的恶魔已经死了
至少被赶走了
My demons are dead or chased off.
是的，除了这个与你同床缠绵的恶魔
Yes, apart from the one lingering monster
with whom you share a bed.
我想你能自己找到衣服和门
I trust you can find your clothing
and the door.
你应该没忘记那个女人
是如何折磨我们妹妹的吧
You do recall that woman
tortured our sister?
也是她才让我知道了我们妹妹的背叛
She also revealed the truth
about our sister's treachery.
正因如此，蕾贝卡永远地离开了我们
And as a consequence,
Rebekah is gone forever.
我想她一定早有此意
A desire which she apparently
harbored for quite some time!
尼克劳斯，已经一个月了
Niklaus, it has been a month.
我和你一样痛心失去我们的妹妹
Now, I feel our sister's loss
as deeply as you.
你不能再如此放纵自己
继续过这种荒唐的生活
You must stop distracting yourself
with this ridiculous behavior
而是将悲伤转化为力量
and channel it
into some kind of action.
我为什么要这样做？
Why must l, exactly?
因为在马赛尔掌权的这些年
这城市已习惯了有国王的统治
Because over the course
of Marcel's tenure,
the city grew accustomed
to having a king.
既然你想要这个宝座
You wanted this throne.
你就必须承担随之而来的责任
You must accept the responsibility
that accompanies that.
很抱歉
Apologies.
但我更想追求别的东西
But I'm rather ensconced
in other pursuits.
如果你能如此轻易抛弃这个家
If you can so easily neglect your home,
我真不知道你的女儿将来会怎样
I wonder what will become
of your daughter.
难道你已经忘了
在暴力的威胁下生存的滋味了吗？
Have you forgotten what it was like
to live beneath the threat of violence?
我们必须同心协力，尼克劳斯
We must work together, Niklaus.
让我们来重建这个城市吧
Let's make this city whole again.
或许已经伤害太深，无法补救了
Perhaps it is too broken to mend.
如果你不愿意做的话，那我来
If you won't do anything, I will.
片名：创始吸血鬼（第一季）
剧名：波旁街之月
圣安妮教堂一直是这个城市
的中立之地
FATHER KlERAN: St. Anne's has long been
neutral ground in our city.
所以我们今天聚集于此
主演：约瑟夫摩根
So, it's only fitting
that we gather in this chamber
应以利亚米卡森的要求
at the behest of Elijah Mikaelson
为这个我们称之为家的地方带来和平
to bring harmony
to this place we call home.
谢谢大家过来
主演：丹尼尔吉利斯
-Thank you all for coming.
没错，谢谢，欢迎各位
-Yes, thank you, and welcome.
这是马赛尔杰拉德订下的规矩
主演：菲比托金
These are the rules of the city
according to Marcel Gerard.
主演：查尔斯麦可戴维斯
当然不再有任何效力
Which of course no longer apply
因为如今我做主
主演：莉雅派普斯
because I am in charge.
你说过如果我们出席的话
主演：丹妮儿坎贝尔
You said if we came along,
你会同意让我们自己做主
主演：丹妮儿坎贝尔
we would run things by ourselves.
你可没说过自己要当国王
Never mentioned anything
about making yourself king.
你们是从每个群体中推选出来的代表
You were each selected to represent
your own communities,
我对此表示尊重
I'll honor that.
但如果不同势力之间起了冲突
那就由我来解决
However, issues which arise
between factions will come to me.
我们每个人或多或少都对这个城市
当下的泥乱状况有些责任
Now, we are all, to some extent,
responsible for the current chaos.
但你们都面对着一个非常简单的选择
However, you have one very,
very simple choice ahead of you here.
大家一起和平共处
不然就离开这里
You can all play nicely together,
or you can leave.
看，黛维娜，很容易的
只要努力就行
See, Davina? It's easy.
All you have to do is try.
我在努力了
I am trying.
怎么努力都还是失败
自从你回来后就一直这样
Trying and failing,
ever since you came back.
你什么时候才能不再针对我
制片：克里斯多福贺利尔
When are you gonna stop
being such a bitch to me,
莫妮克？
Monique?
当你不再软弱的时候
制片：兰斯安德森
When you stop being weak.
你本来是个收获祭女孩
但或许你不属于这里
You're supposed to be a Harvest girl,
but maybe you don't belong here.
或许你从来就不属于这里
Maybe you never did.
你不是应该去跟那群小子
拚个你死我活吗？
Shouldn't you be out there
playing Fight Club
with the rest of the frat boys?
不用，这只是为了争夺族群地位
That's just for pecking order.
他们早就知道谁是老大了
They already know who's the Alpha.
制片：邦妮怀斯
下一个，来吧
Next up! Let's go!
你一定要尝尝塔克做的肋排
You got to try Tucker's ribs.
然后呢？
编剧：蜜雪儿侃洛戴斯
Then what?
再去玩玩马蹄铁吗？
编剧：克里斯多福贺利尔
Then we're gonna go play horseshoes?
别嘲笑乡村生活，亲爱的
导演：麦可罗宾森
-Don't mock country living, darling.
抱歉
-Sorry.
我还不习惯这种快乐的家庭生活
This is just a lot more family fun
than I'm used to.
也许我能帮你适应这种生活
Well, maybe I can help you
get used to it.
所以我们要做的就是忘记
OLlVER:
Then all we got to do is just forget
她此生一半时间与人类生活
she spent half her life with humans
另外一半与吸血鬼生活的事实
and the other half with vampires.
- 奥利，别说了
- 没关系
-Ollie, back off.
-It's okay.
小矮个儿有话说，那就说吧
If the runt of the litter
has something to say, he should say it.
你知道吗，法语区都在说你的男人
以利亚正在举行什么权力高峰会
Word from the Quarter is your boy
Elijah's holding some power summit.
猜猜谁没受到邀请
Guess who wasn't invited.
- 你从哪里听来的？
- 那不重要
-Where did you hear this?
-lt doesn't matter.
重点是我们被困在这片沼泽
The point is, we're stuck here
living in the swamp
而你的吸血鬼男友
却在决定着城市该如何分配
while your vampire boyfriend's
deciding who gets what in the city.
但我想这也能证明他到底有多
尊重狼人族群，是吧？
I guess that shows how much respect
he's got for the werewolves.
这也是我们的城市
(CROWD ARGUlNG)
This is our city, too.
- 我们应该可以去任何想去的地方
- 我们会认为那就是宣战
We should be able
to go wherever the hell we want.
这样毫无进展
你们这群卑鄙的生物无法同意…
Nowhere.
You vile creatures cannot agree--
神父，请冷静
Father, calm yourself, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
现在回到边界的问题
你们都得遵守以下规定
Now, about the issue of boundaries,
you will all heed to the following.
你是认真的吗？
HAYLEY: Are you serious?
你们在瓜分城市
而狼人竟然都没有发言权？
You're dividing up the city,
and the werewolves don't get a say?
- 她来这里干什么？
- 迪亚哥，坐下
-What the hell is she doing here?
-Diego, sit.
我们没有在瓜分城市
我们是在建立…
-We're not dividing the city--
不，以利亚
-No, Elijah!
如果你们把狼人排除在外
和平就不可能存在
There is not gonna be a peace
if the werewolves are excluded.
他们也想在谈判中有一席之地
They want a seat at the table.
如果没有
HAYLEY: And if they don't get one,
我敢保证你们都会后悔的
I can guarantee
that you will all regret it.
绝对不可能
我们会发动一场这城市前所未见的战争
WOMAN: We will start a war the likes
of which this city has never seen.
你知道光是把刚才那些人
聚集在同一个房间里有多困难吗？
Do you have any idea what it took just
to get those people in one room together?
事实上，我不知道
No, actually, I don't.
因为要不是有人告诉我
Because I didn't even know
what you were doing out here
我都不知道你们在这里做什么
until someone else told me.
告诉我，以利亚
Tell me something, Elijah.
你是因为我才把狼人排除在外的吗？
Did you leave the werewolves out
because of me?
我把他们排除在外是因为他们
不再住在法语区了
I excluded them because they no
longer reside in the French Quarter.
我的当务之急是要解决这里
日益增长的冲突
My immediate concern is to end
the mounting conflict here.
我向你保证，一旦协定确立
Now, I can assure you
once this treaty is solidified,
马上就会把你的族人纳进来
it will expand
to include your people.
在那之前呢，我要怎么跟他们说？
坐下，别动，打个滚吗？
Until then, I should tell them what?
Sit, stay, roll over?
我情愿你不要参与这件事
I'd prefer that you remove yourself
from the process altogether.
海莉，你真的确定
Hayley, are you absolutely certain
你不回到宅邸住吗？
that you shouldn't return
to the compound?
你觉得孩子属于那里吗？
You think the baby belongs there?
你觉得她在那里才会安全吗？
You think that's where she'll be safe?
难道河口就更好吗？
Is the bayou any better?
狼人应该有发言权
The wolves deserve a voice.
给他们发言权
Give them one.
你知道这样做才是正确的
You know it's the right thing to do.
你真该看看海莉进来时
你哥哥的表情
You should have seen
your brother's face when Hayley walked in.
看来新月诅咒被打破了
Crescent curse is broken then?
你觉得这能行得通吗？
Do you believe
this will actually work?
这个城市真的能够拥有和平吗？
That we can finally have some
semblance of peace in this city?
我从院子里看到你的灯亮着
就想赌一下…
I saw the light from the courtyard
and took a chance that...
你没和一个半裸的神经病女巫在一起
...you weren't
with a half-naked psycho-witch.
看来我赌输了
Seems I gambled and lost.
十分钟前，我是全裸的
Ten minutes ago,
I was fully naked.
那你的目的已经达到了
不耽误你了
Oh. Then you served your purpose.
Don't let me hold you up.
你们欧康诺家的人可真爱跟女巫找茬啊
You O'Connells sure do love
to piss off witches.
这是真的吗？
GENEVlEVE: Really?
那个女人曾经威胁我
The woman tried to blackmail me
into stabbing you
要我用神秘的刀刺你，让你痛不欲生
with the Mystical Knife
of Excruciating Pain.
奇怪的床伴就是纽奥良的特产啊
Well, New Orleans breeds nothing
if not strange bedfellows.
但我想你来这里应该不是因为
我的休闲生活吧
I assume you're not here to question me
on my leisure activities.
我来是为了我叔叔的事
他的病情在恶化
I'm here about my uncle.
He's deteriorating.
药物、冥想，都不管用了
The pills, the meditation,
they're not working.
他越来越不清醒了
His lucidity's shrinking by the day.
女巫下的咒，女巫可以解
Awitch did this,
a witch can undo it.
看来你跟洁妮薇的关系很好
也许你能说服她帮忙
You seem supertight with Genevieve.
Maybe you can persuade her to help.
没用的
It won't do any good.
这种诅咒是由魔法开始的
These hexes, they start with magic,
一旦生根
它们就会改变大脑的化学物质
but as they take root,
they alter the very chemistry of the brain.
我很抱歉，卡蜜
伤害已经无法挽回了
I'm sorry, Cami.
The damage is done.
我才不接受这种说法
I refuse to accept that.
如果你有家庭观念的话，你也不会接受
And you would, too,
if you had any concept of family.
小约
Josh.
黛维娜，你来这里干什么？
Davina, what are you doing out here?
你想在哪里见面我都可以过去
I would have met you
anywhere you wanted.
我是说，没有克劳斯和马赛尔的地方
I mean, not anywhere
Klaus or Marcel would be,
虽然他们俩几乎无处不在
which could be pretty much,
you know, anywhere.
但你明白我的意思
But you know what I mean.
嘿，你还好吗？
Hey. You okay?
是莫妮克
It's Monique.
她不知道我死后经历了什么事
She has no idea what I went through
when I was dead.
祖先因为我用魔法所做的一切而憎恨我
The ancestors hated me
for what I did with my magic.
我不能重新使用魔法了
I can't just start practicing again.
我知道马赛尔要我回去时我不该相信他
I knew I shouldn't have trusted
Marcel when he told me to go back.
我不知道我还能忍受多久
I don't know
how much more of it I can take.
- 又和那小女巫闹别扭了吗？
- 我能搞定
THlERRY:
On the outs with the witch again?
I got it covered.
什么事这么重要
你还要把我带来这里？
What was so important you dragged me
all the way out here?
我有个提议
I have a proposal.
我希望你和所有跟着你离开克劳斯的人
站在我这边
I want you and all who walked out
on Klaus with you to join me.
- 召集军队吗？
- 没有军队就不能收回城市了
-Rounding up an army?
-Can't take back the city without one.
你一无所有
You have nothing.
没有武器，没有同盟
No weapons, no allies.
甚至一旦你靠近法语区
以利亚就会杀了你
You go even close to the Quarter,
and Elijah will kill you.
如果克劳斯没先杀死你的话
That's if Klaus doesn't get you first.
所以呢，也许我该和你一样
躲在巴克镇吗？
So, what, maybe I should hide out
in Bucktown like you?
我想你同意来见我是因为
你不想离开你的家
I think you're here 'cause
you don't wanna leave your home.
我当然也不想离开我的家
I sure as hell don't wanna leave mine.
战争一触即发，小提
A battle is brewing, T.
大家都忙着选择阵营
While everyone's busy
choosing sides,
我会想办法夺回我们的城市，所以…
I'm gonna find a way
to take back our city, so...
你要和我一起吗？
You with me?
你总是说得好听，马赛尔
You were always great with words,
Marcel.
但这次除了高谈阔论还得有些别的
But it's gonna take
more than a pretty speech this time.
真的有这必要吗？
Is that really necessary?
这种病，正在逐渐
压过我宽恕的意愿
The sickness,
it's overtaking my inclination to forgive.
在高峰会上，我满脑子只有一个念头
Replacing it with one thought that
I could barely contain at the summit.
把他们统统杀死
"Kill every last one of them."
我们会想出办法的
We'll figure it out.
我之前试图帮助西恩
I tried to figure it out with Sean.
但我太专注于此
而没能试图阻止他
But I was focused too much on that
instead of trying to stop him.
我不会让这一切发生在我身上
And I'm not--
I'm not gonna let that happen to me.
你是欧康诺家的人
You're an O'Connell.
他们会叫你接替我的位置
They are going to ask you
to take my place at the table.
别答应，离开这里
Don't. Just leave.
重新开始
Just start over.
只要还有机会我就哪都不会去
I'm not going anywhere
as long as there's still a chance.
我要跟你说多少次
我没法恢复了
How many times do I have to tell you
I can't be fixed?
我要跟你说多少次
我绝不会放弃尝试
How many times do I have to tell you
I will not stop trying?
真是太顽固了
跟你小时候一样
That is just stubbornness,
like when you were a little girl.
你总是要证明自己是对的
你从不听话
You always had to be right.
You... You never listened.
真是太愚蠢了
Just that thick head of yours.
我为你祈祷
I prayed for you.
没有回应
And I got no answer.
只有黑暗
There is only blackness.
只有死亡
There is only death.
有我的
There's mine.
还有你的
And yours.
不，不，不要
No, no, no!
不要
No!
- 米卡森先生
- 科雷亚女士
-Mr. Mikaelson.
-Miss Correa.
请叫我佛朗西丝卡
Please call me Francesca.
我们可以省去那些客套话了
科雷亚女士
We can dispense
with any formalities, Miss Correa.
我知道你是谁
I know exactly who you are.
你是皇宫赌场的老闪
You own the Palace Royale Casino.
你是城里重要的慈善家之一
You're one of the city's
leading philanthropists.
据我所知，你还是一位
And according to my sources,
you're the matriarch
相当庞大的贩毒帝国的首领
to a rather sizeable
drug trafficking empire.
为什么找我来？
-So why am I here?
-Whatever you may think of me,
不管你怎么想我
我的家族多年来都是人类决策群的一员
my family's been a part
of the human faction for years.
这就让我有资格接替基兰神父的位置
Which makes me uniquely qualified
to take father Kieran's place.
从现在起，你将和我打交道
You'll deal with me from now on.
你是在命令我吗？
Are you giving me a mandate?
不是
No.
(LAUGHS)
我是要和你结盟
I'm giving you an ally.
我和你一样想要和平
I want peace just as much as you do.
我非常喜欢的生活方式
My lifestyle,
which I enjoy very much,
依赖和平
depends on it.
是的，我看得出你非常积极
Yes,
I can see you're highly motivated.
你知道吗，我应该告诉你
You know, I should mention,
我已经和新市长、警察局长
和其他利益相关团体
I've already spoken to the
city's new mayor and the chief of police
谈过了
and other interested parties,
他们都支持我
and I have their blessing.
你会发现有我站在你这边对你有利
I think you'll find it beneficial
to have me on your side.
即使只能够避免我不太文明的同胞
Even if it's just to prevent
my less civil brethren
从各方面攻击而给你们带来不快
from lashing out in ways
that could prove painful to you.
祝你今晚愉快
Have a good night.
不喜欢天蓝色吗？
Not a fan of cerulean blue?
不喜欢你继续这么漠不关心
Not a fan
of your continued indifference.
要想让一个曾经互相憎恨的群体
Well, it's difficult
trying to unite a community
团结起来是很难的
that has a history of mutual loathing.
- 省省你那些陈腔滥调吧，尼克劳斯
- 那就说点有建设性的
-Spare me the platitudes, Niklaus.
-A perspective then.
如果你想要和平，你首先要从狼人开始
If you want peace,
you must begin with the werewolves.
一百年前，他们统治着这个城市
A hundred years ago,
they had a run at ruling this city.
随后，他们只能够
As of late, all they've had is time
看着他们的敌人
毁掉一切他们的辛苦成果
to watch their enemies
tear down that legacy.
这正是为什么他们的敌人
不愿让他们重回谈判桌
All the more reason why their enemies
are reluctant to bring them to the table.
学学比恩维尔，哥哥
Take a page from Bienville, brother.
如果谈判桌是个障碍
那就挪开它
If the table's the obstacle, remove it.
你还记得1720年
Do you recall in 1720
总督迫切希望得到我们的帮助
the governor's desperation
to secure our help
建造城市的第一个防洪堤吗？
to build the cities first levees?
我们和他谈了，拒绝了他
We sat with him
and refused his offer.
所以他不断奉上美酒和穿胸衣的女人
And so he plied us with wine,
with corseted women,
不停套交情，直到我们答应他为止
and with raucous camaraderie
until he had his yes.
你是建议我办个派对吗？
Are you suggesting
that I throw a party?
让我惊叹啊，哥哥
I'm impressed, brother.
是啊，如果我能不让他们把彼此
撕成碎片就好了
Yes, now if I can just keep them
from tearing one another to shreds.
那么为了你，敬超级无聊的夜晚
Then for your sake,
here's to a spectacularly boring evening.
怎么了，小个子？
What's up, little man?
他不值得你动手
He's not even worth it.
既然你心事重重
我就凭直觉想像你的赞美好了
Since you're preoccupied,
I'll intuit your flattering compliment.
谢谢，我也觉得我很美
Thank you.
I think I look stunning, too.
我相信你挑选礼服的时间
I trust you've spent as much time
fortifying alliances
与你加强同盟的时间一样多
as you clearly have
selecting that dress.
这么说你的确注意到我了
So you do notice me.
是的，我已经处理好码头的纠纷了
And, yes, I've already settled
the dispute over the docks.
我答应女巫提高她们墓地旅游的分成
I pacified the witches with
an increased share in cemetery tours,
我也给了新月族重新变回人形的贺礼
and I've given the Crescents
a welcome back to humanity gift
我赌场里价值一百美金的筹码
in the form of 100 dollar chips
to my casino.
我想，我应该来杯香槟，你说呢？
So, I think I deserve some champagne,
don't you?
你知道，考虑到基兰不断恶化的病情
You know, in light
of Kieran's deteriorating condition,
其他人默许了你的提议
the others have acquiesced
to your proposal.
你将代表人类决策群直到他重新回来
You will represent the human faction
until he's ready to resume.
那我们可要好好利用这有限的时间了
Then I suggest we make the most
of our limited time together.
天啊
God.
听着，你要是指望我向你求饶
我不会再这么做了
If you expect me to beg for my life,
that's not me anymore.
你以为我是来杀你的？
我是为黛维娜而来
You think I'm here to kill you?
I'm here about Davina.
你听说高峰会的事了吧
You heard about the summit.
如果谈判破裂
If it falls apart,
每一方都会寻找筹码来对付其他方
each faction's gonna look
for leverage against the other ones.
黛维娜得能够保护自己
Davina has to be able
to defend herself,
如有必要，还得防着自己人
even from her own people if need be.
她必须要再次使用魔法
She has to start doing magic again.
你为什么跟我说这些？
Why are you telling me?
因为得有人告诉她
而她又不会听我的
Because someone has to tell her,
and she won't listen to me.
所以怎样，我告诉她
然后你试图让她重回你的阵营
So, what, I tell her, and you try
to get her back on your side.
是吗？继续拿她当你的私人武器？
Right, go back to using her
as your personal weapon?
我不在乎她最终会站在哪边
I don't care whose side
she ends up on,
只要她安全就好
just that she's safe.
因为我们都知道现在她并不安全
Because we both know
right now she isn't.
迪亚哥
Diego.
你要彬彬有礼表示欢迎
You will be polite and welcoming.
是啊，他的族人杀了我全家
Yeah, see,
his people killed my whole family.
我妹妹就躺在我旁边，流血过多而死
My sister bled out on the floor
right next to me.
我现在还能站在这里
The only reason I'm standing here
是因为马赛尔出现
在我血流干之前转变了我
is 'cause Marcel came along
and turned me before I bled out too.
所以我现在告诉你
So, I'm telling you right now.
我不可能彬彬有礼表示欢迎
I cannot be polite
and welcoming to that.
迪亚哥，我理解你的愤怒
Diego, I understand your anger.
然而，如果我们想要某种程度的和平
However, there are certain overtures
that need to be made
就必须稍稍示好
if we are to find a degree of peace.
欢迎来我家
Welcome to my home.
要不是海莉强烈要求，我是不会来的
I wouldn't be here
if Hayley hadn't forced the issue.
是的，你不太可能在这里
Yes, it's rather unlikely
that you'll experience
受到热情洋溢的款待
an outpouring of kind sentiment here.
特别是吸血鬼都将你们视为…
The vampires in particular
view you as...
野蛮人
...well, barbaric.
海莉告诉我这个和平协定
对你来说很重要
Hayley tells me this peace treaty
is important to you.
是的，确实很重要
Yes, it certainly is.
所以说
So much so, in fact,
如果有任何人威胁要毁掉
我在这里建立的一切
that if anyone threatened
to dismantle what I'm building here,
我就会毁掉他们珍视的一切
I'd destroy everything they hold dear.
祝你今晚开心
Have a wonderful evening.
在我你的心理医生吗？
Looking for your shrink?
别告诉我你嫉妒卡蜜了，亲爱的
Don't tell me
you're jealous of Cami, love.
只是好奇你怎么会找她作伴
Just curious
why you'd seek her company.
她看起来很…普通
She seems so ordinary.
有时候，普通让人愉悦，让人放松
Well, sometimes,
ordinary is a welcome respite.
我还以为我能让你放松呢
I thought I was your respite.
你能啊
Well, you are.
你能
You are.
答应我别再想卡蜜了
Promise me
not another thought about Cami.
我很高兴你接受了我的邀请
I'm so glad
you accepted my invitation.
伟大的克劳斯米卡森要在这里
So, is this where the great
Klaus Mikaelson
说些尖锐的话然后扭断我脖子吗？
says something poignant
and snaps my neck?
我不是来杀你的
我是要给你一份礼物
I'm not here to kill you.
I'm here to offer you a gift.
出于你那吸血鬼的好意吗？
Out of the kindness
of your vampire heart?
其实你我比你以为的要相似
Our hearts are more similar
than you might realize.
早在我进化之前
我也是狼人
You see, long before I evolved,
mine beat as a werewolf.
我了解你们的能力
I know your power.
也了解你们的烦恼
I know your burden.
我是来为你们消除后者的
I'm here to take the latter away.
你想把我变成混合种
You want to make me a Hybrid.
我以我的族人为重
I put my pack first.
我不会让任何事危害到我的家族
And I'm not gonna let anything
compromise my family line,
特别是变成嗜血的吸血鬼寄生虫
especially becoming
some bloodthirsty vampire parasite.
那种自豪感
That pride...
那种忠诚
That sense of loyalty...
正是我到现在还没扭断你脖子的原因
Well, that's exactly why
I haven't snapped your neck yet.
如果你不打算杀我
那你到底想干什么？
Well, if you're not gonna kill me,
then what the hell do you want?
只是要把从你们手里
夺走的城市还给你们
Only to give you back
the city that was taken from you.
这尖锐吗？
How was that for poignant?
我为什么要相信一个
Why would I trust someone
背着自己哥哥搞鬼的人？
who's conspiring
behind his own brother's back?
我不是要破坏以利亚的计划
I'm not trying
to undermine Elijah's venture.
我是在支持他
I'm supporting his vision.
吸血鬼靠杀人来生存
Vampires destroy life to survive,
女巫逐渐衰落
witches are only as powerful
as their dead.
但狼人却日益壮大
The werewolves have thrived
因为他们的力量来自于家族的团结
because their strength
comes from family unity.
这样的团结正是我想要让
我未出生孩子所拥有的
The safety of that unity
is what I want for my unborn child.
令人不快的事实却是
The painful truth is...
吸血鬼从来就不团结
...vampires are the antithesis of unity.
所以怎样？
So, what?
一千年之后，你终于准备好接受
After a thousand years,
you're finally ready to embrace
你的另一半血统吗？
the other half of your family tree?
或许那一半并不欢迎你
Maybe the other half doesn't want you.
他们会的
只要能让他们回到法语区
Oh, they will
once they return to the Quarter.
你有什么计划吗？
You got a plan to back that up?
我母亲是个十分强大的女巫
My mother was a very powerful witch.
我见过她制作各式各样的魔法物品
I watched her craft
all manner of magical items.
但对她来说最宝贵的是这枚戒指
But her most prized possession
was this ring.
我已经有一千年没见过它
I hadn't seen it for a thousand years,
然后它出现了，挂在一个狼人的脖子上
and then it turned up hanging around
the neck of a werewolf,
我生父的直系后代
a direct descendant
of my biological father.
我相信我母亲给了他这枚戒指
是为了让他自由
I believe she gave him this ring
as a way of freeing him.
怎么说？
How so?
日光戒指保护吸血鬼不受阳光侵害
Daylight rings shield vampires
from the sun.
那为什么不能有一个月光戒指
So, why not a moonlight ring
保护狼人免受诅咒之苦呢？
to protect werewolves
from the curse?
想想看
Think about it.
不需再遭受断骨的痛苦
No more breaking bones.
不再受内心的野兽控制
No more losing control
to the beast within.
你想要我怎么做？
What do I have to do?
嘿
Hey.
- 你看起来…
- 紧张
-You look...
-Nervous.
格格不入，还是这礼服显得我很矮？
Out of place, short in this dress?
我本来想说美丽动人
I was gonna say pretty.
我叫奥利佛
I'm Oliver.
不知这位我想邀她共舞的小姐
叫什么名字？
So, what's the name of the girl
I'm about to ask to dance?
她叫莫妮克
Her name is Monique.
能请你跳支舞吗？
Would you care to dance?
派对办得真不错
You outdid yourself.
你甚至还说服了克劳斯参加
You even got Klaus
to come out and play.
如今恐怕也只有靠大型派对
Yes, it seems
that only a sizeable soiree
才能让我弟弟从画架旁离开了
is enough to tear my brother away
from his efforts at the easel.
这听起来可不妙
That's never a good sign.
克劳斯曾对我说过
他画画是为了控制自己
Klaus once told me that his painting
was a metaphor for control,
他会用尽各种手段
来实现自己内心的想法
for achieving his vision
through sheer force of will.
说实话，如果他那脑袋里
Well, truthfully, I'd be shocked
没有至少十几个阴险狡诈的想法
if he didn't have at least
a dozen or so of those visions
我才会奇怪呢
swarming around
in that insidious skull of his.
我衷心希望你女儿能遗传到她母亲的…
I do hope your daughter
inherits her mother's--
所有一切
Everything.
- 回到这里的感觉很奇怪
- 希望不是不愉快的感觉
-lt is weird being back here?
-Not unpleasant, I hope.
不完全是
Not entirely.
你确定不回来跟我们一起生活吗？
Are you entirely sure
you shouldn't be here with us?
为什么，以利亚？
Why, Elijah?
是因为你觉得
我跟那些狼人在一起不安全吗？
Because you don't think it's safe
in big, bad wolf country?
我可不会坐在摇椅上织婴儿袜
I'm not gonna sit in a rocking chair
and knit booties,
你到现在还不明白吗？
or haven't you figured that out yet?
- 能跟你谈谈吗，海莉？
- 你可以等会再谈
-Can I have a minute, Hayley?
-You can have it later.
事实上，他可以与我共舞这一曲
Actually, he can have this dance.
- 一切还好吗？
- 是的，没事
-Everything all right?
-Yeah. Fine.
我们只是在讨论这个城市的将来
We were just discussing
the future of the city.
这时候你怎么还想着这个城市？
How can you be thinking
about the city right now?
我真该告诉你你今晚有多迷人
I should have told you
how beautiful you look tonight.
别紧张，别紧张
Easy. Easy.
要薄荷酒吗？不过这里面没有糖和薄荷
Julep, minus the sugar and mint?
我刚刚见了基兰
他不会再伤害你了
I just saw Kieran.
He's not gonna hurt you again.
事实上，他离不开那个阁楼了
In fact, he won't leave the attic at all.
我找人施了个边界咒
I arranged
for a little boundary spell.
你找到女巫帮你了？
我还以为她们都恨你
You got a witch to help you?
I thought they hated you.
为了你，我找到了一个不那么恨我的
For you, I found one who doesn't.
- 怎么了？
- 没事
-Hey, what's wrong?
-Nothing.
你是这一个月来第一个帮我的人
You're the first person
to help me in a month.
基兰是我唯一的亲人
Kieran's the only family I have left.
没有他，我就是一个人了
Without him, I'm alone.
我明白
Yeah.
这些日子我也失去了很多亲人
Yeah, I'm a little short
on family myself these days.
如果有任何能帮到你的，卡蜜
尽管开口
Hey, if there's anything I can do to help,
Cami, just let me know.
是有件事
There is one thing.
我们的波本酒喝光了
We're out of bourbon.
狼人小子
Hey, wolf boy.
该叫他们帮你用饲料碗盛吗？
Should have had them
put it in a bowl for you?
你希望我用那个敲碎你的脑袋吗？
Well, yeah, if you want me
to crush your skull with it.
别这样，小伙子们
能争点有意义的事情吗？
Please, boys.
At least, fight over something interesting.
比如说我？
Me perhaps?
你不会想跟他们扯上任何关系的
No, you don't want to get involved
with his kind.
他们总喜欢无故发狂
See, they got this nasty,
little habit of going berserk
然后将无辜的人撕成碎片
and ripping innocent people
to shreds.
不不，好吧，听着
No, no, no. Okay, look.
如果我的族人做过任何伤害到你的事
我向你表示深切的歉意，好吗？
If my people wronged you in any way,
you have my condolences, okay?
不过如果他们都长得像你一样丑
我的族人绝对下不了口
I'd be surprised if my kin could choke
them down, being half as ugly as him.
现在就给我结束
This ends now.
- 我不会再说第二遍
- 放心，我们会结束这一切的
-I won't ask again.
-Oh, we'll end it all right.
你为什么不动手？
HAYLEY: What's stopping you?
杀了他
Kill him.
来啊，以利亚，动手吧
Go ahead, Elijah. Do it.
反正他死有余辜
I mean, it's not like
he doesn't deserve to die.
难道这时候你不该出面吗？
Shouldn't you intervene or something?
为什么？
这派对才刚刚开始有意思
Why would l?
This party just got interesting.
正是奥利佛把蕾贝卡交给了女巫
It was Oliver who handed Rebekah
over to the witches
让她受到百般折磨
so they could torture her.
但话说回来，上个月那场
But then again, wasn't it Diego
狼人大屠杀不正是迪亚哥带头的吗？
who led a werewolf massacre
last month?
而当女巫对狼人下咒时
And the witches cursed the wolves,
那些人类也只是站在一旁冷眼旁观
while the humans stood back
and let it all happen.
这么想的话
这里的所有人都该死
So when you think about it,
everyone here deserves to die.
你想说什么？
Are approaching a point?
我想说的是，以利亚
My point, Elijah, is this.
如果我们不能和平共处
If we can't all learn to get along,
如果我们各自的族群不能联手合作
if our families can't create
some sort of community,
那还有什么意义？
then what's the point?
不如杀掉彼此早点了事
Kill each other
and get it all over with.
我这辈子只收到过一次玫瑰花
JOSH: You know, I've only gotten
roses once in my life.
- 都没能保留下来
- 为什么？
-Didn't even get to keep them.
-Why not?
我的第一个男朋友，也是唯一一个
My first boyfriend,
my only boyfriend really,
毕业那年的情人节送给我的
gave them to me
for Valentine's Day senior year.
我试图把花藏在卧室
但被我父母发现了
Tried to hide them in my bedroom,
but my parents found them.
你可能不知道，但玫瑰花
会堵塞住最好的碎纸机
You may not know, but roses will jam
even the best paper shredders.
我没有家可回
You know,
I don't have a home to go home to.
或者一个接纳我的家庭
Or a family to go home to.
我曾因此恨我自己
I used to hate myself for that.
但事实是
But the thing is...
我真的不再在乎他们怎么想了
...I don't really care
what they think anymore.
如果你的家人不喜欢你现在的样子
管他们呢
If your family doesn't like you
the way you are, screw them.
你有我
有卡蜜
You got me and Cami.
如果你愿意，还有马赛尔
Even Marcel if you want.
马赛尔利用了我
Marcel used me.
他利用你去对付试图杀死你的人
He used you to fight the people
who were trying to kill you.
你知道，他也从那些人手中救了你
所以…
And, you know, he also saved you
from those people, so....
你不必相信他
但他的确爱你
You don't have to trust the guy,
but he does love you.
另外
And PS...
我也爱你
...so do l.
即使我没有魔法吗？
Even if I don't have any magic?
我所拥有的法力都来自于
其他收获祭的女孩
All the power I had
was from the other harvest girls.
我都不知道没有它我还有什么
I don't even know
what I have without it.
难道你不该自己去搞清楚吗？
Don't you owe it to yourself
to find out?
你是女巫，黛维娜
You're a witch, Davina.
你和我一样不能改变自己的本质
You can't change your DNA
any more than I can.
所以你不妨试着去接受
So, you might as well embrace it.
- 你还好吗？
- 只是擦伤
-You okay?
-Just some bruises.
- 我擦伤还没好呢
- 来
-I'm still bruised.
-Come on.
“擦伤”真是个有趣的词
"Bruise" is such a funny word.
发音和“酒”好像
我们还有酒吗？
It sounds like "booze."
Do we have any more booze?
没了，我想我们都喝完了
No, I think we drank it all.
你是个好朋友，马赛尔
You're a good friend, Marcel.
你该躺下休息了
You should lie down.
我受够了总是一个人
I'm tired of being alone.
我也是
I am too.
并不是说这样不好
Not that that wasn't totally worth it.
但绝对不能再发生了
It can never happen again.
要是我们当中有谁又想喝薄荷酒了呢？
What if one of us craves another julep?
不知为何，克劳斯信任我
For whatever reason,
Klaus trusts me,
而你大概是他现在最恨的人
and you're the person
he probably hates most right now.
他会觉得这是背叛
He'd see it as a betrayal.
这对我们俩都没好处
That wouldn't be good for either of us.
马赛尔
Marcel.
这真的非常棒
It really was totally worth it.
是的
Yeah, it was.
你说我一无所有
你错了
You said I had nothing.
You were wrong.
我有和第一次从灰烬中
重建这座城市时一样的东西
I have the same thing I had when l
rebuilt this city from the ashes the first time.
再无可失，获得一切
Everything to gain
and nothing to lose.
我有了进展，建立盟友
最重要的就是黛维娜
I'm making inroads, allies,
not the least of which is Davina.
除非我确定可以指望你
否则我不会离开这屋顶
And I'm not leaving this roof
until I can count you in too.
此外，我们说实话吧，小提
你只有我了
Besides, let's be honest, T.
I'm all you got.
我了解那些吸血鬼
他们不只是离开宅邸
I know those vampires,
they didn't just leave the compound.
他们彻底离开了纽奥良
They left New Orleans.
我们俩对抗全世界吗？
So, us against the world?
我们会有第三第四个伙伴
We'll get a third and a fourth.
很快，我们就会拥有整支军队
And pretty soon,
we're gonna have that army.
一切改变都从计划开始
KLAUS: All change begins with a plan.
（纽奥良 和平协定）
计划的成功取决于几个因素
The success of which
depends upon several things.
承诺的深度
Depth of commitment.
对目标的热情
Passion for one's cause.
- 嘿，敬海莉
- 敬海莉
-Hey! To Hayley!
-To Hayley!
开辟新路的意愿
KLAUS:
Willingness to embrace a new path.
克服一切困难的决心
Determination
to overcome any obstacle.
而有时
甚至是结交超乎寻常的同盟
And in some cases,
even making unnatural alliances.
你和克劳斯米卡森做了交易？
You made a deal
with Klaus Mikaelson?
我宁愿每个月圆日变身
I'd rather turn every full moon.
如果克劳斯没说错
If Klaus is right,
这个魔法不仅能阻止我们变身
this magic could do more
than just stop us from turning.
我们最终可以控制自己
We could finally control
what we are.
我们可以利用一切力量、一切速度
We could draw on all the strength,
all the speed,
我们狼形时的原始力量
the raw power of our werewolf form.
我们的咬伤将随时能让吸血鬼毙命
Our bite would be lethal to vampires
24/7.
猎杀我们的人类
诅咒我们的女巫
The humans who hunt us,
the witches who curse us,
憎恨我们的吸血鬼
我们将不再只与他们势均力敌
the vampires who hate us,
we wouldn't just be their equals.
我们将统治他们
We'd be their superiors.
- 签字
- 为什么？
-Sign it.
-Why?
你已经代表我方签了字
You've already done so
on our behalf.
弟弟，我不是傻瓜
Brother, I'm not a fool.
我很清楚其实你并不像表现出来的
那样漠不关心
You're not as disinterested
as you'd like me to believe.
请签字
Sign, please.
如果你我都不能和平相处
If there is no peace between us,
那你怎么能指望其他人跟随呢？
then how can you expect others
to follow suit?
好吧
如果这能让你开心
Fine.
If it will make you happy.
但我向你保证，这个城市的居民
不会遵守这个协定的
I assure you this city's inhabitants
will not adhere to this agreement.
欢迎你跟我打赌
Well, you are welcome
to wager against me.
你会输的
You will lose.
走着瞧吧
We'll see.
片名：创始吸血鬼（第一季）